Irene Smith

845-699-2258 • irenesmith13@gmail.com http://www.irenesmith.com • @Story Teller

Summary

Hybrid developer/technical writer, with over 30 years' experience with multiple programming languages and technologies. Comfortable with full stack development of both native applications for Windows as well as website and web-based applications. Extensive experience writing API documentation, design and requirement documents, and release notes.

Technical Skills

Windows Application Development: C# and VB.NET, VBA, Java, C, C++, Python

Web Development: HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap, ASP .NET, ASP 3.0

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft Access, MongoDB

Graphics and Video: Adobe PhotoShop, Adobe Lightroom, PaintShop Pro, Gimp, Microsoft Visio,

Snaglt, OBS Studio, Adobe After Effects, Jingo

Source Control: Git, Perforce, Visual Source Safe (VSS), SVN, Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Writing Tools: Microsoft Office, Google Docs, RoboHelp, Scrivener, Open Office

Development Tools: Sublime Text 3, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), DOS, macOS

Professional Experience

Amazon Web Services Code Example Developer Programmer Writer

3/2023 - Present 9/2020 - 2/2023

Responsibilities

- Developed C# code examples for the AWS SDK for .NET.
- Participated in an initiative to simplify the inclusion of code examples in developer documentation by including specialized comments in the code.
- Develop scenario applications, applications that perform basic tasks for a single AWS service, and cross-service code examples, applications that use multiple AWS services, usually in the form of an ASP .NET application with a React.is front-end.
- Act as on call for the code examples build process which includes creating test builds on a virtual desktop, then initiating the actual build process on the build servers, and then trouble-shooting any problems that arise.

Mozilla

Firefox Developer Content Manager
On contract through Harvey Nash

6/2018 - 11/2019

Responsibilities

- Manage content for MDN Web Docs Browser Extensions and Firefox Developer Tools
- Write tutorials for web development.
- Update and refine existing content to reflect new and updated Firefox features and web development best practices.
- Create example code for tutorials and web APIs.

MongoDB

Technical Writer

9/2017 - 3/2018

Responsibilities

- Wrote documentation for MongoDB Atlas
- Collaborated with developers to document new features of MongoDB.

Resume of Irene Smith Page 2

Created web documentation for MongoDB using restructured Text (reST) and Sphinx.

Moody's Analytics

Technical Writer 11/2016 - 6/2017

On contract through Randstad Technologies

Responsibilities

- Worked with developers to create technical documentation for Cloud Computing Project
- Created stylesheets and documentation templates.
- Helped define processes for support, development, and technical documentation projects.
- Created quick guides, workflows, and high-level overviews for end users.

Credit Suisse, New York, NY

Technical Writer

5/2016 - 9/2016

On contract through Insight Global

Responsibilities

- Interviewed Developers to create technical documentation for CCAR Application Modules
- Helped to create SAD (Software Architecture Documentation) document for CCAR Application
- Created data flow and architectural diagrams and application screenshots.
- Wrote reference materials for use by support personnel in application troubleshooting.

BNP Paribas, New York, NY

Developer

6/2015 - 12/2015

On contract through Huxley Associates

Responsibilities

- Wrote C# console applications that are run as automated processes to update trade data.
- Created VBA Scripts for Microsoft Excel that create reports for traders.
- Enhanced the UI of a stock pricing application that uses MVC, Angular, and Bootstrap
- Wrote, reviewed, and edited project requirements and user stories.

TIAA-CREF, Charlotte, NC (Remote)

Senior Technical Writer

11/2013 - 2/2015

On contract through Stratus Technologies, LLC

Responsibilities

- Create and maintain templates and VBA macros to simplify document creation.
- Create and update the Developer's Reference for the PRISM API, an application that uses Oracle coherence to cache mainframe data for a Java API
- Create and update a data dictionary for use by PRISM developers.
- Create and update walkthroughs for the PRISM application that include step-by-step instructions and screenshots.

Google, Inc., New York, NY 10011

Technical Writer III, on one-year contract through Apex Systems, Inc.

7/2012 - 7/2013

Responsibilities

- Wrote technical guides and other documentation using HTML5, CSS3, and markdown.
- Wrote and maintained API documentation for the following Ad Exchange technologies: Buyer REST API, Seller REST API, Buyer SOAP API, Real-time Bidding Protocol
- Wrote the developer's guide for Google's open-source project, Open Bidder

Medidata Solutions, Inc. New York, NY 10003

Senior Programming Technical Communicator Senior Technical Communicator, Team Lead

1/2010 – 1/2012 1/2008 - 1/2010

Technical Communicator

9/2006 - 1/2008

Resume of Irene Smith Page 3

Responsibilities

- Scrum Master for internal tools for the Technical Communications department
- Used C# to develop ASP .NET applications, Windows applications, and Microsoft Word add-ins. These tools reduced document preparation time from days to minutes
- Used SQL Server to design and create database model for all internal tools including table design, stored procedures, and functions.
- Lead and mentored, and trained colleagues in creating design specifications and requirements.
- Team Lead for multiple documentation projects.

Times Herald Record, Middletown, NY 10940

Paginator, Assistant Obituary Editor

2/2005 - 1/2006

Responsibilities

- Developed a set of Microsoft Word macros to automate the process preparing obituaries, thus reducing preparation time from over half an hour to less than one minute.
- Documented obituary and classified preparation procedures.
- Prepared obituaries and classified advertising for printing.

Microsoft, Redmond, WA 98052

Programming Writer (FTE), SQL Server Group

4/2000 - 10/2003

Responsibilities

- Developed samples for the **System.Data** namespace of the .NET Framework for versions 1.0, 1.1, and 2.0 using C# and VB .NET to create console and ASP .NET applications.
- Used C++, Visual Basic 6.0, Java (Microsoft J++), JavaScript, and VBScript to develop console application examples for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references.
- Developed examples for Microsoft XML using C++ and Visual Basic

mpl2.com, Bellevue, WA

Programming Writer (on contract at Microsoft)

8/1999 - 3/2000

Originally called Meridian Partners, Ltd., mpl2.com placed writers in contract positions at various locations in Redmond, Bellevue, and Seattle including Microsoft.

Responsibilities

- Wrote conceptual and API reference documentation for Microsoft's database objects.
- Used C++, Jscript, Visual Basic 6.0, VBScript, and Java to develop ASP 3.0 and console example applications for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references.

CRS. Newburgh, NY

Application Developer

4/1998 - 8/1999

Responsibilities

- Developed and maintained all modules in the Point-of-Sale suite.
- Designed and developed a data warehousing application that rolls up sales data on a daily basis for retail customers.

Solo Game Development

Designed, coded, created graphics, and wrote context-sensitive help files for several Microsoft Windows commercial game packages:

- Casino Nights (Craps, Roulette, Black Jack, and Video Poker)
- Dice Games (Crag, Over 'n Under, and Bird Cage)
- Solitaire (Pyramid and Golf)

Education

University of Phoenix, Online

BS Information Technology/Software Design

Resume of Irene Smith Page 4

Orange County Community College, Middletown, NY AA, Liberal Arts